# RODOLFO PEINADO GUERRERO

# Front End Software Engineer | Web Technologies

+57 3053725583 @ rodolfguerr@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a skilled software architect with 10 years of expertise in front-end ecosystems. Since 2016, I have focused on creating superior React applications for high-traffic services using leading-edge solutions. As a professional committed to excellence, I welcome opportunities to work on projects where innovation aligns with stakeholder objectives. Over the past decade, I specialized in the front-end ecosystem. I am also comfortable working in full-stack environments.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Front End Engineer

06/2022 - Present

#### DevCrew I/O

Singapore, Singapore

- Designed and implemented micro front-end architecture to modularize front-end products into reusable pieces, allowing different front-end frameworks to work together, developed in TypeScript using principles of Flux architecture.
- Led development of web components that are core elements of an initiative to unify the design system across the company, used across multiple products and teams developed in TypeScript.
- Built a web app for capturing and signing sales contracts, agnostic to the document design and printing technology.
- Created a progressive web app for desktop and mobile as a prototype to showcase feasibility for desktop-like keyboard-heavy interactions, developed in React.
- Built an extension for the company's flagship product allowing it to utilize a new user interface running inside an older JavaScript framework. Implemented analytics to track issues and performance that helped identify pre-launch issues.
- Created a JavaScript library to simplify the execution of test steps and assertion for an in-house developed JavaScript framework

## Front End Engineer

02/2019 - 04/2022

DOOD

Hong Kong, Hong Kong

- Created in-house developer tools and design systems.Introduced modern architectural solutions and changes to old and new systems.
- Initiated a shared interoperable component ecosystem across codebases with different stacks.
- Used custom tools and leveraged pre-built Docker images to improve a CI/CD pipeline.Participated in research and development tasks driven by new initiatives.
- Defined global, company-wide standards for front-end developers.
- Concluded over 100 interviews with positive feedback from candidates about the process.
- Built an internal portal for front-end developers—featuring the latest news, a package browser with documentation, changelog history, and a Storybook playground—and an online version of our front-end cookbook.

#### **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### Reduced Load Times

Spearheaded the redesign of a major application, reducing load times by 30%, enhancing customer satisfaction.

### Boosted User Engagement

Implemented accessible design principles, resulting in a 25% increase in user engagement across devices.

## Enhanced Development Efficiency

Introduced new development frameworks, increasing team efficiency by 18% and accelerating project delivery.

#### Mentorship Excellence

Successfully mentored over 10 junior developers, significantly improving the team's overall skill set and productivity.

#### **SKILLS**

ReactJS · NextJS · VueJS ·
NuxtJS · Angular.js · HTML/CSS ·
JavaScript · TypeScript ·
Tailwind CSS · Material UI

#### **CERTIFICATION**

## Advanced NextJS Development

Focused on server-side rendering and static generation techniques, provided by Coursera.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Junior Frontend Developer

## **West Road South**

02/2014 - 12/2018

Hong Kong, Hong Kong

- · Learned and utilized an in-house CMS to create websites.
- Converted PSDs to HTML for back-end developers to implement using the CMS.
- Built responsive EDMs to be deployed via Campaign Monitor.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to solve issues with creating the website after providing them with the HTML.
- Managed contractors to ensure they created quality work with good code, matching the design requirements.
- Worked with universities, financial institutions, and other big clients like Rheem water heater manufacturer, Wattyl paint manufacturer, and Bottlemart retail alcohol distributor.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's in Computer Science

Jiangnan University

04/2009 - 12/2013

#### **CERTIFICATION**

# React and Modern JavaScript

Covers hooks, contexts, and advanced components, offered by Udemy.